<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./ddbquery.png" type="Source"
    xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Amazon DynamoDB Query</name>
    <shortDescription>
        Retrieves data from DynamoDB by hash key and a filter for the range key.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node queries DynamoDB and returns the matching attributes as KNIME table.
            Important: the columns and their types of the KNIME output table are determined from the
            first batch of items retrieved from DynamoDB. One batch has a maximum size of 1MB. If an item
            in a later batch, i.e. after loading 1MB, has an attribute that did not occur before, this attribute
            is not written to the output table.
        </intro>
        <tab name="Standard Settings">
            <option name="Region">The region the table is in.</option>
            <option name="Table Name">The table to access.</option>
            <option name="Custom Endpoint" optional="true">A custom endpoint if the default AWS endpoint should not be used, e.g. for DynamoDB Local.</option>
            <option name="Hash Key">The hash key of the items to retrieve.</option>
            <option name="Range Key">A filter on the table's range key.</option>
            <option name="Index name" optional="true">The name of the index to use or empty if no index should be queried.</option>
            <option name="Consistent Read">Whether consistent read should be enforced (costs twice the throughput capacity units).</option>
            <option name="Limit">The maximum number of items to retrieve.</option>
            <option name="Publish consumed capacity units as flow variable">
            If checked, the total capacity units used by the operation are published as a flow variable named &quot;queryConsumedCapacity&quot;.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Filter &amp; Projection">
            <option name="Filter">
                A filter expression (see <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazondynamodb/latest/developerguide/Query.html#Query.FilterExpression">the DynamoDB documentation</a>)
            </option>
            <option name="Projection">
                The attributes to load from DynamoDB.
            </option>
            <option name="Name Mapping">
                Mapping for name placeholders in the filter and projection expressions. Necessary if the attribute names are reserved keywords.
            </option>
            <option name="Value Mapping">
                Mapping for value placeholders in the filter and projection expressions.
            </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Amazon Credentials">Credentials for an AWS account</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Amazon Credentials">Credentials for an AWS account</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Query results">KNIME data table with query results</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>

