<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./ddbcreatetable.png" type="Other"
    xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>DynamoDB Create Table</name>
    <shortDescription>
        Creates a new DynamoDB table.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
            This node creates a DynamoDB table with optional global and local indexes in the given region.
            </p>
        </intro>
        <tab name="Standard Settings">
            <option name="Static credentials">
            If checked, credentials can be entered in the node dialog, otherwise the AWS default credentials provider chain is used,
            which looks for credentials in this order:
            <ul>
            <li>
            Environment Variables - AWS_ACCESS_KEY_ID and AWS_SECRET_ACCESS_KEY, or AWS_ACCESS_KEY and AWS_SECRET_KEY
            </li>
            <li>
            Java System Properties - aws.accessKeyId and aws.secretKey
            </li>
            <li>
            Credential profiles file at the default location (~/.aws/credentials) shared by all AWS SDKs and the AWS CLI
            </li>
            <li>
            Credentials delivered through the Amazon EC2 container service
            if AWS_CONTAINER_CREDENTIALS_RELATIVE_URI" environment variable is set
            and security manager has permission to access the variable,
            </li>
            <li>
            Instance profile credentials delivered through the Amazon EC2 metadata service
            </li>
            </ul>
            </option>
            <option name="Access Key">The access key for access to the AWS infrastructure.</option>
            <option name="Secret Key">The secret key for access to the AWS infrastructure.</option>
            <option name="Region">The region the table is in.</option>
            <option name="Table Name">The table to access.</option>
            <option name="Custom Endpoint" optional="true">A custom endpoint if the default AWS endpoint should not be used, e.g. for DynamoDB Local.</option>
            <option name="Hash Key">The name and type of the table's hash key.</option>
            <option name="Range Key">If unchecked, the table has no range key. Otherwise the name and type of the range key must be given.</option>
            <option name="Billing Mode">Whether the table access is billed per request or via provisioned throughput.</option>
            <option name="Read Capacity Units">The number of read capacity units provisioned for the table (min. 1, max. 40.000).</option>
            <option name="Write Capacity Units">The number of write capacity units provisioned for the table (min. 1, max. 40.000).</option>
            <option name="Block until table is active">If checked, the node blocks execution until the table is ready for reading and writing.</option>
            <option name="Tags">Tags assigned to the table for ressource management.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Indexes">
            <option name="Type">
            The type of index. Global indexes' keys can be defined on any scalar attribute,
            local indexes have the same hash key as their parent table.
            </option>
            <option name="Name">
            The name of the index.
            </option>
            <option name="Hash Key">
            The name and type of the attribute serving as a hash key for the index.
            </option>
            <option name="Range Key">
            If checked: the name and type of the attribute serving as a range key for the index. Otherwise the index has no range key.
            Local indexes always have a range key.
            </option>
            <option name="Read Units">The number of provisioned read units if the index is global.</option>
            <option name="Write Units">The number of provisioned write units if the index is global.</option>
            <option name="Projection">The type of projection, i.e. the attributes included in the index.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
            <option name="Enable SSE">Enables Server-Side Encryption</option>
            <option name="KMS Master Key ID">The ID of the KMS master key to use or empty if the default key should be used</option>
            <option name="Enable Streaming">Enables streaming of table changes</option>
            <option name="Stream View Type">Which attributes to include in the stream</option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Amazon Credentials">Credentials for an AWS account</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Flow Variables" optional="true">Flow variables for table settings</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Amazon Credentials">Credentials for an AWS account</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
