<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./ddbbatchget.png" type="Source"
    xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Amazon DynamoDB Batch Get</name>
    <shortDescription>
        Retrieves data from DynamoDB by hash and range key.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        <p>
        This nodes retrieves items from DynamoDB that match a given hash and optional range key in a KNIME table.
        </p>
        <p>
        The command sent to DynamoDB by this node is BatchGet, with a single batch retrieving
        at most 100 items.
        </p>
        <p>
        If DynamoDB throttles the requests due to insufficient
        provisioned capacity units, unprocessed items are included in the next request.
        Additionally this node employs exponential backoff if throttling occurs. Each time a request
        cannot be completed fully, the next request is sent after a waiting time of 2&#94;nRetry * 100 milliseconds.
        Once a request can be executed completely, the retry counter is reset.
        However, if no item can be retrieved, the node fails and you have to increase the provisioned read
        capacity units on the table.
        </p>
        More information can be found in the
        <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/de_de/amazondynamodb/latest/APIReference/API_BatchGetItem.html">DynamoDB documentation</a>.
        </intro>
        <tab name="Standard Settings">
            <option name="Region">The region the table is in.</option>
            <option name="Table Name">The table to access.</option>
            <option name="Custom Endpoint" optional="true">A custom endpoint if the default AWS endpoint should not be used, e.g. for DynamoDB Local.</option>
            <option name="Batch Size">The number of items to retrieve in a single batch (max. 100, min. 1).</option>
            <option name="Hash Key Column">The column in the input KNIME table containing the hash key of the items to be retrieved.</option>
            <option name="Range Key Column" optional="true">The column in the input KNIME table containing the range key of the items to be retrieved.</option>
            <option name="Publish consumed capacity units as flow variable">
            If checked, the total capacity units used by the operation are published as a flow variable named &quot;batchGetConsumedCapacity&quot;.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Projection">
            <option name="Projection" optional="true">
            A projection expression determining which attributes to retrieve.
            See <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/en_en/amazondynamodb/latest/developerguide/Expressions.ProjectionExpressions.html">the DynamoDB documentation</a>.
            </option>
            <option name="Name mapping">
            Placeholder names and values for attribute names in the projection expression that do not conform to the norm for attribute names or are reserved keywords.
            </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Amazon Credentials">Credentials for an AWS account</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="KNIME table">KNIME data table with keys of items to be retrieved</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Amazon Credentials">Credentials for an AWS account</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="KNIME table">KNIME data table with retrieved items</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>

