<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./ddbbatchdelete.png" type="Sink"
    xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Amazon DynamoDB Batch Delete</name>
    <shortDescription>
        Deletes data from DynamoDB by hash and range key.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        <p>
        This nodes deletes items in DynamoDB that match a given hash and optional range key in a KNIME table.
        </p>
        <p>
        The command sent to DynamoDB by this node is BatchWriteItem, with a single batch deleting
        at most 25 items, so deleting a large amount of data may take a while. The individual
        delete operations on item level are atomic, but the operation is not atomic on batch
        or even node execution level. That means if the node fails in-between, some of the items
        may have been deleted and others not.
        </p>
        <p>
        If DynamoDB throttles the requests due to insufficient
        provisioned capacity units, unprocessed items are included in the next request.
        Additionally this node employs exponential backoff if throttling occurs. Each time a request
        cannot be completed fully, the next request is sent after a waiting time of 2&#94;nRetry * 100 milliseconds.
        Once a request can be executed completely, the retry counter is reset.
        However, if no item can be deleted, the node fails and you have to increase the provisioned write
        capacity units on the table.
        </p>
        More information can be found in the
        <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/de_de/amazondynamodb/latest/APIReference/API_BatchWriteItem.html">DynamoDB documentation</a>.
        </intro>
        <option name="Region">The region the table is in.</option>
        <option name="Table Name">The table to access.</option>
        <option name="Custom Endpoint" optional="true">A custom endpoint if the default AWS endpoint should not be used, e.g. for DynamoDB Local.</option>
        <option name="Batch Size">The number of items to delete in a single batch (max. 25, min. 1).</option>
        <option name="Hash Key Column">The column in the input KNIME table containing the hash key of the items to be deleted.</option>
        <option name="Range Key Column" optional="true">The column in the input KNIME table containing the range key of the items to be deleted.</option>
        <option name="Publish consumed capacity units as flow variable">
        If checked, the total capacity units used by the operation are published as a flow variable named &quot;batchDeleteConsumedCapacity&quot;.</option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Amazon Credentials">Credentials for an AWS account</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="KNIME table">KNIME data table with keys of items to be deleted</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Amazon Credentials">Credentials for an AWS account</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>

